Carmen Melaragno

71 Pearl Drive Cellular: (860) 459.8754 Vernon, CT 06066 cmelarag@yahoo.com

SUMMARY:

I am a versatile, energetic, and proactive professional with integrity, excellent work ethic, and results-oriented. My experience includes strategic business planning, customer service, finance, accounting, sales & marketing, and operations. The skills contributing to my career success include: strong oral communication skills, organizational and analytical skills, quality-oriented, team player and the ability to adapt to change rapidly.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE:

The Hartford Hartford, CT

Hartford Investment Management Company

Senior Strategic Marketing Consultant – Thought Leadership

July 2009 - Present

- Collaborate to drive the Firm's *Thought Leadership* strategic initiative through active employee engagement across HIMCO
- Partner with marketing and investment professionals to capture and communicate the Firm's views and opinions on the macro economy and portfolio strategies.
- Manage Thought Leadership 'Idea Pipeline' to identify topical and thought-provoking ideas, measure success and maintain an avenue for feedback exchange.
- Manage web site content and enhancements, and establish metrics related to Thought Leadership.

Key Accomplishments:

• Improved and maintained 'time-to-market' of critical Thought Leadership pieces by 60%.

Virtus Investment Partners, Inc.

Hartford, CT

(Formerly Phoenix Investment Partners)

Director, Market Research

March 2008 – May 2009

- Analyzed mutual fund market to identify trends and drivers in the marketplace, business environment and products.
- Prepared Board presentations and identified talking points for senior management.
- · Conducted analysis and assessments of potential new products, fund adoptions, manager searches and product line.
- Developed key reporting packages and trend analysis to communicate findings to key constituents and senior management.
- Analyzed, reviewed and negotiated departmental contracts resulting in annual savings of over \$300,000.

Alpha Capital Research, LLC.

Glastonbury, CT

Hedge Fund of Funds

Director, Investment Operations and Accounting

March 2007 – March 2008

- Managed operational, accounting and marketing responsibilities to support the company's financial and business goals.
- Supported and assisted the portfolio managers in tracking investment manager data and performance figures.
- Initiated and developed written summary of analysis and due diligence of existing and potential new investments.
- Ensured compliance with accounting and anti-money laundering.
- Oversaw annual audit of hedge funds and tax preparation for the company.
- Primary point-of-contact for all client communications from pre-investment to post-investment stages.

Phoenix Life Insurance Company, Inc.

Hartford, CT

Phoenix Investment Partners

Product Manager

March 2005 - March 2007

- Interfaced with Marketing, Compliance and Legal to manage the coordination and preparation of quarterly materials for sub-advised funds.
- Developed marketing strategy for line-up of investment mutual funds.
- Supported and managed the development of new product initiatives.
- Prepared monthly and quarterly reports and presentations for the board relative to competitive landscape.
- Managed the completion of RFP's and maintained the integrity of information within the database.
- Run Adhoc reports through host systems (Simfund, Zephyr, Morningstar, and Lipper).

Carmen Melaragno

71 Pearl Drive Cellular: (860) 459.8754
Vernon, CT 06066 cmelarag@yahoo.com

Phoenix Life Insurance Company

Distribution Analyst

August 2002 - March 2005

- Distribution Compensation Analyst and Relationship Manager to largest Distributor relationship.
- Subject Matter Expert, Business Lead and liaison for Life and Annuity Product Development.
- Contributed to saving over \$1.5 million for the department.

Merrill Lynch Hartford, CT

Private Client Group

Associate Service Manager

August 2001-August 2002

- Assisted in managing and overseeing the direct operations for the Hartford Complex (100 Advisors, 20 Associates).
- Worked with Financial Advisors to manage client accounts.
- Led the consolidation effort of three offices into the Hartford Main Complex office.

Financial Advisor August 1999 – August 2001

- Assisted individuals in identifying their distinct financial needs and objectives.
- Recommended plans and products to help achieve short and long-term goals.

Gerald Metals, Inc. Stamford, CT

Credit Analyst

October 1997 – August 1999

- Analyzed financial statements in order to assess credit worthiness of each relationship.
- Construed all data and formulated a credit recommendation to credit committee.
- Generated and interpreted reports illustrating company exposure.
- Supervised and monitored all collection obligations.
- Successfully managed day-to-day operations of Credit Department.

Accounts Receivable Coordinator

May 1997 – October 1997

Major: Finance, GPA 3.2

- Posted cash applications and reduced receivables by 70%.
- Resolved unpaid claims and reconciled month end bank statements.

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND:

University of Hartford, May 2005 Post University, 1997
Masters in Business Administration B.S.: Business Administration

Concentration: Finance, GPA 3.6

LICENSES & PROFICIENCIES:

- Series 7, Series 66, Life Insurance and Annuities
- Bloomberg
- PackHedge
- QuickBooks
- Zephyr Style Advisor
- Morningstar Direct, Principia Pro, Advisor Workstation
- Strategic Insight Simfund/MF, Simfund/TD
- PMAPS
- Callan
- Evestment